Paul A. W. Wallace Papers 1895-1940 Mss.Ms.Coll.64b
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1754-1966 (Box 1-11)
  - Nicolls, Frederick W., 1948-1949; 8 items
  - Nolan, J. Bennett (James Bennett), 1877-1964, 1935-1937, 1947; 9 items
  - North Carolina State Library, 1936; 2 items
  - Northampton County Historical and Genealogical Society, 1939; 2 items
  - Ohnedagowah (Great Pine) Forest Theatre -- Sixth Annual Pageant, 1954; 1 item
  - Okie, John M., n.d.; 1 item
  - Oneida County Historical Society (Oneida County, N.Y.), 1937; 1 item
  - Onondaga Historical Association, 1937; 2 items
  - Osborn, Stellanova (Mrs. Charles S.), 1962-1963; 3 items
  - Overman, William Daniel, 1901-, 1937; 3 items
  - Pargellis, Stanley McCrory, 1898- -- Loudoun Papers, 1933; 1 vol.
  - Parke-Bernet Galleries, 1947; 2 items
  - Parker, Arthur Caswell, 1881-1955 -- Constitution of the Five Nations (copy 1), 1916; 71 items
  - Parker, Arthur Caswell, 1881-1955 -- Constitution of the Five Nations (copy 2)
  - Parker, Arthur Caswell, 1881-1955, 1936; 20 items
  - Parker, Arthur Caswell, 1881-1955, 1948-1954; 18 items
  - Parker, Mrs. Arthur C.
  - Peckham, Howard Henry, 1910-, 1952; 2 items
  - Peters, Nichodemus, 1936; 7 items
  - Philadelphia Yearly Meeting of the Religious Society of Friends -- Kinzua Dam Controversy: A Practical Solution--Without Shame, ca. 1961; 1 vol.
  - Pierpont Morgan Library, 1948; 1 item
  - Port Allegany Reporter-Argus (Port Allegany, Pa.) -- Five issues, 1924; 5 items
  - Potier, Pierre-Philippe, 1708-1781 -- Huron-French Vocabulary, n.d.; 39 items
  - Potter, Lloyd G., 1948; 1 item
  - Powell, John H., 1948; 10 items
  - Powers, Frederick, 1957; 2 items
  - Public Archives of Canada, 1936; 5 items
  - Radabaugh, James H. -- Schoenbrunn and the Moravian Missions in Ohio, 1950; 1 vol.
  - Randle, E.P., 1936; 3 items
  - Randolph, Corliss Fitz, 1863-, 1937; 2 items
  - Raven Grey Eagle, 1963; 3 items
  - Reading Public Museum and Art Gallery (Pa.), 1937; 2 items
  - Reformed Churches of Stone Arabia and Sprakers (Palatine Bridge, N.Y.), 1937; 4 items
  - Reibel, Daniel B. -- Guide to Old Economy Third and last home of the Harmony Society 1824-1905, 1966; 25 items
  - Reigner, Etta, 1937; 1 item
  - Rhode Island Historical Society, 1948; 2 items
  - Richards, H. Branson, 1937; 2 items
  - Richards, John W., 1940; 3 items
  - Richmond, Donald, 1958; 2 items
  - Rickard, Chauncy, 1937; 1 item
  - Riley, Stephen T., 1936; 5 items
  - Ritchie, William Augustus, 1903-, 1947-1948; 12 items
  - Roberts, Elizabeth R. (Mrs. Owen), 1961; 10 items
  - Rochester Museum of Arts and Sciences, 1954; 1 item
  - Royal Ontario Museum, 1937; 2 items
  - Rutledge, Anna, 1958; 40 items
  - Ryerson Press, 1947; 2 items
  - Sa-Hiuhushu, B., 1946; 2 items
  - Schoharie County Farm Bureau News, 1938; 1 vol.
  - Schoharie County Historical Society -- Old Stone Church and Fortress: Catalogue and Historical Notes, 1933; 1 vol.
  - Schwab, Norman, 1937; 1 item
  - Schwarze, William Nathaniel, 1875-1948, 1936; 6 items
  - Sellers, Charles Coleman, 1903-, 1947-1958; 11 items
  - Serres, John, 1961; 9 items
  - Shawnee Indians -- Bibliography, 2 items
  - Shawnee Indians -- Sketch of History of Absentee Shawnees (extract from Civilization of the American Indian, two copies), 1936; 10 items
  - Shelling, Richard I., 1950; 2 items
  - Shenk, H.H., 1937; 2 items
  - Shenton, Donald, 1950; 2 items
  - Shoemaker, Henry W., 1880- -- Early Jewish Pioneers in Dauphin County, Pennsylvania (Talk)
  - Shoemaker, Henry W., 1880-, 1946; 2 items
  - Siksika Indians -- Bibliography, 4 items
  - Simmers, Helen K. (Mrs. C. Elmer), 1960; 3 items
  - Site and Relic Society of Germantown (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1937; 1 item
  - Six Nations -- Indians Travel to Washington, 1959; 1 item
  - Six Nations -- Publications: Ka-Weh-Ras newsletter (22 issues), 1947-1948; 22 items
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Journal, 1936; 50 items
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Journal, 1937; 8 items
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Journal, 1955; 21 items
  - Smith, Mildred Rohm (Mrs. Edward L.), 1937; 8 items
  - Smith, William, 1948; 2 items
  - Smithsonian Institution, 1937, 1949; 3 items
  - Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-, 1954; 1 item
  - Souder, Marguerite, 1937; 5 items
  - South Carolina State Library, 1936; 1 item
  - Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950, 1936-1946; 20 items
  - Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950, 1946-1947; 16 items
  - Springfield City Library (Mass.), 1937; 2 items
  - Spyker, Maria, 1937; 2 items
  - Stabley, Jane, 1940; 1 item
  - State Historical Society of Wisconsin, 1936-1937, 1948; 10 items
  - State Library of Pennsylvania, 1937; 2 items
  - Stitson, Mrs. Earl N., 1937; 2 items
  - Stoudt, John Baer, 1878-, 1935-1942; 9 items
  - Strawn, Robertson, 1940; 2 items
  - Swaine, Francis A., n.d.; 16 items
  - Swigart, W. Emmert, 1939; 4 items
  - Syracuse Historical Society, 1937; 1 item
  - Taylor, Herbert L., 1961; 1 item
  - Tehanetorens -- Conservation as the Indian Saw It, 1 item
  - Tehanetorens -- Great Gift, Tobacco, n.d.
  - Tehanetorens -- Hermit Thrush, ca. 1963; 1 item
  - Tehanetorens -- Iroquois Lesson Book: Stories for Good Children and Bad, 21 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Miscellaneous items, n.d.; 15 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Seven Dancers, 1 item
  - Tehanetorens -- Six Nations Iroquois Confederacy Record (World War II), n.d.; 1 item
  - Tehanetorens -- Visions of Handsome Lake, 81 items
  - Tehanetorens, 1947-1950; 112 items
  - Tehanetorens, 1951-1955; 101 items
  - Tehanetorens, 1956-1961; 90 items
  - Tehanetorens, 1962-1964; 79 items
  - Tehanetorens, 1965-1967; 27 items
  - Thayer, Theodore, 1904-, 1940; 2 items
  - Theiss, Lewis E. (Lewis Edwin), 1878-1963, 1937; 2 items
  - Tonawanda Community News, 1952; 1 vol.
  - Trappe (Pa.)--Buildings, structures, etc., ca. 1948; 15 items
  - True, Rodney Howard, 1866-, 1936; 2 items
  - Unger, C.W., 1937; 3 items
  - United States Department of the Interior Geological Survey, 1956; 6 items
  - United States National Museum, 1959; 4 items
  - University of Chicago, 1948; 1 item
  - University of Illinois, 1948; 1 item
  - University of Pennsylvania Press, 1939-1948; 97 items
  - University of Pittsburgh. Press, 1964; 132 items
  - University of Virginia, 1936; 1 item
  - Valley Forge Park Commission, 1948; 2 items
  - Van Doren, Carl, 1885-1950, 1948-1939, 1946; 7 items
  - Van Dyke, D., 1961; 1 item
  - Vandersloot, Charles Edwin, 1938; 1 item
  - Vesper, Herman F., 1937; 3 items
  - Vincent, Florentine, 1948; 2 items
  - Virginia State Library, 1936; 3 items
  - Voegelin, C. F. (Charles Frederick), 1906-, 1940; 4 items
  - Wagner, Augusta W. (Mrs. Jesse L.), 1948; 10 items
  - Wainwright, Nicholas B., 1958; 2 items
  - Wallace, Dorothy (Clarke) -- Wallace, Paul A.W. Letter from, ca. 1936; 8 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Camp Greble "Pow-Wow" (Talk), ca. 1950; 22 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Conrad Weiser (talk), 1960; 8 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Conrad Weiser reviews, 1945-1946; 18 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Debt We Owe the Indian (talk), 1949; 80 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- De-Ka-Nah-Wi-Deh: Notes, manuscripts, and interviews with William Dewaseragech Loft., 1937-1961; 39 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Delawares-as-Women Problem, 1952; 77 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- French-Canadian Folklore, 1920; 36 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- French-Canadian Folklore, 1920; 39 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- French-Canadian Folklore, 1920; 53 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- French-Canadian Folklore, 1920; 36 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- French-Canadian Legends, 1920; 36 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Heckewelder, John--Talks, 1954-1960
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Hope Lodge (Montgomery County, Pa.), n.d.; 2 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indian Highways of Pennsylvania, 44 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indian Highways, 1950; 15 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indian Highways, 15 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indian Paths (Talk), 1957-1958; 18 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indian Preacher, 33 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indian Renaissance, 1947-1948; 17 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indian Trails (Talks), 1951-1952; 23 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indian Trails and Pennsylvania Travelers, 1951; 115 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indian Trails: Notes, 5 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indian Village, 2 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indian Way of Life, 23 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indians of Our Valley (Talk), 1953
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indians of Pennsylvania (Talk), 1965; 33 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indians: Talks, 1964-1965; 28 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indians--Talks (notes), ca. 1964; 24 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indians--Talks: Cohen, Felix S. Americanizing the White Man (from American Scholar 21: 2 (1952), p. 181, 8 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Indian-White Relations, ca. 1960; 49 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Iroquois as an International Power (Talk), n.d.; 2 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Iroquois Nation Welcomes You: A Visit to the Six Nations Reserve, 1936; 40 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Iroquois: A Brief Outline of their History, n.d.; 16 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Jacob Eyerly's Journal, 1794: The Survey of Moravian Lands in the Erie Triangle (reprint), 1962; 13 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- John Heckewelder Papers, n.d.; 17 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Last King of the Delawares (Joseph Montour), two copies, n.d.; 10 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Local History (Talk), 1958; 3 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Logan and His People (Talk), 1 item
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Men Who Carried the Flag on Indian Paths (Talk), 1 item
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Moravian Records, n.d.; 125 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Moravians (Talks), n.d.; 29 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Muhlenberg Family (Talk), 1949; 26 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Muhlenberg Women (Talk), n.d.; 34 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Muhlenbergs of Pennsylvania: Revisions, 1963; 5 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Muhlenbergs: Acknowledgements, 3 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- My Favorite Pennsylvanians (Talk), 1961; 3 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Our Indian Trails (Talk), 1949; 22 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Our Indian Trails: Luckhurst, Charlotte. Narrative of the Captivity of Mrs. Jane Whittaker, Daughter of Sebastian Strope, a Revolutionary Soldier, 1930; 1 vol.
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Return of Hiawatha, 1948; 42 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Sakayenkwarahton and General Sullivan Travel the Great Warriors Path, 1966; 53 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Seven Wonders of Pennsylvania (Talk), 1 item
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Shickellamy (Talk)
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- They Knew the Indian: The Men who Wrote the Moravian Records, 42 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Thirty Thousand Miles with John Heckewelder: Readers' comments, presentation copies, errata, 6 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Travels in Indian Country (portions), 43 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Travels in Indian Country (sample pages of proposed book), 64 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Travels in Indian Country, 1 item
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Travels in Indian Country, 17 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Travels in Indian Country, 1 item
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Travels in Indian Country, 2 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Travels in Indian Country, 3 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Travels in Indian Country, 1 item
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Travels in Indian Country, 8 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Travels in Indian Country, 2 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Travels in the Indian Country, 2 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Travels in the Indian Country, 7 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- We are the Six Nations (three copies), n.d.; 15 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- White Roots of Peace (reviews), 1946-1947; 22 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Who Were the Hurons' Allies of 1615?, n.d.; 8 items
  - Wallace, Paul A.W. -- Will, 1962; 1 item
  - Wallace, Paul A.W.
  - Washington and Lee University, 1936; 2 items
  - Wasielewski, Hans Th. v., 1937; 12 items
  - Weer, Paul, 1950-1954; 24 items
  - Weiser, Conrad, 1696-1760 -- Deeds (correspondence regarding), 1936; 2 items
  - Weiser, Conrad, 1696-1760 -- Illustrations (map of Indian nations), 1 item
  - Weiser, Conrad, 1696-1760 -- Notes and Correspondence Regarding, 1936-1964; 100 items
  - Weiser, Conrad, 1696-1760 -- Notes, n.d.; 19 items
  - Weiser, Frank, 1937; 2 items
  - Weiser, Frederick Sheely, 1935- -- Reasons for Conrad Weiser's Migration to Pennsylvania, n.d.; 4 items
  - Weiser, Frederick Sheely, 1935-, 1956; 4 items
  - Weiser, Lucy, 1937; 7 items
  - Weiser, W.R., 1937; 1 item
  - Weslager, C. A. (Clinton Alfred), 1909-, 1943-1946; 16 items
  - West Virginia. State Library, Charleston, 1936; 2 items
  - Western Reserve Historical Society, 1948; 1 item
  - Weygandt, Cornelius, 1871-1957, 1936; 13 items
  - Wheeler, George, 1935-1940; 36 items
  - Wheeler-Voegelin, Erminie, 1903-, n.d.; 1 item
  - Wilkins, Frederick H., 1937; 3 items
  - William H. Allen Bookseller (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1949; 1 item
  - William L. Clements Library, 1948; 2 items
  - Williams, Isaiah, 1936; 1 item
  - Wilson, Edmund, 1895-1972, 1960; 2 items
  - Winchester, Virginia Historical Society, 1937; 2 items
  - Winslow, Bernice Minton (Dawendine "Dawn") (Mrs. Arthur H.), 1943-1947, 1955-1956; 77 items
  - Witthoft, John -- Polly Heckewelder's Indian Doll, 3 items
  - Wolff, Ella, 1937; 1 item
  - Wolfkill, George D., n.d.; 1 item
  - World Citizenship Movement, Inc. (Oberlin, Ohio), 1945-1946; 2 items
  - Wray, Charles F., 1962; 2 items
  - Wroth, Lawrence C. (Lawrence Counselman), 1884-1970, 1936; 3 items
  - Wyoming Historical and Geological Society (Wilkes Barre, Pa.), 1937; 3 items
  - Wysor, John, 1939; 5 items
  - Wysor, Nettie, 1937; 6 items
  - Yale University. Library, 1936; 4 items
  - Zeller, A.G. -- Champlain-Iroquois Battle of 1615, 1962; 1 vol.
- Series II. Notebooks, n.d.; 7 items (Othertype Notebooks 1-7)
  - Jesuit Relations Notebooks -- Notes from Reuben Gold Thwaites' The Jesuit Relations, notebooks 1-4, n.d.; 4 vols.
  - Jesuit Relations Notebooks -- Notes from Reuben Gold Thwaites' The Jesuit Relations, notebooks 5-9, n.d.; 5 vols.
  - Weiser, Conrad, 1696-1760 -- Notes on life of Conrad Weiser, 1715-1724, n.d.; 2 vols.
  - Weiser, Conrad, 1696-1760 -- Notes on life of Conrad Weiser, 1725-1734, n.d.; 2 vols.
  - Weiser, Conrad, 1696-1760 -- Notes on life of Conrad Weiser, 1735-1744, n.d.; 2 vols.
  - Weiser, Conrad, 1696-1760 -- Notes on life of Conrad Weiser, 1745-1754, n.d.; 2 vols.
  - Weiser, Conrad, 1696-1760 -- Notes on life of Conrad Weiser, 1755-1764 (d. 1760), n.d.; 5 vols.
- Series III. Graphics, 1885-1964; 7 items
  Wallace Family papers, Native American Images note: Nearly 4,000 black and white silver gelatin photographs; black and white negatives; pencil and ink sketches; photomechanical prints; news clipping photographs; watercolor paintings; postcards; color slides; and maps of Iroquois tribes of the Six Nations Confederacy, particularly Tuscarora and Mohawk, from 1932-1977. Images represent the research of Paul A. W. Wallace and Anthony F. C. Wallace, father and son anthropologist. Paul’s photograph collection presents traditional ethnographic images of social life and customs: dwellings, ceremonies, utensils, clothing, and individual portraits of Iroquois, with half of the material attributed to Akwesasne Mohawk Ray Fadden (Tehanetorens). Anthony’s ethno-psychological emphasis is displayed in images of arctic hysteria suffered by Inuits and traditions of Tuscaroran culture. Of particular interest, pictographs by Lawrence H. Leder of Robert Livingston Indian records, watercolor paintings by Ray Fadden’s son John, original drawings by Seneca Jesse Cornplanter and Tuscaroran Nellie Gansworth, and tintype and carte de visite portraits. Photographs taken by the Wallaces, except where noted. Images can be found in Paul Wallace’s Correspondence, Series I; Anthony Wallace’s Indian research, Series IIa; Graphic Series and Oversize collection. Oversize maps include Native American linguistic and tribal settlement distributions in northeastern United States and southeastern Canada from 1525-1850. Some references in Freeman’s Guide to manuscripts relating to the American Indian and the manuscript sketch files.
  - Bethlehem (Pa.)--Buildings, structures, etc. -- Moravian buildings in Bethlehem. Originally Moravians--Bethlehem., n.d.; 6 items
  - Cornplanter, Jesse J. -- Drawings, 1937
    - Iroquois ceremony, 1937
  - Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823 -- Notes, Amendments, and Additions to Heckewelder's History of the Indians #1-7
  - Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823 -- Notes, Amendments, and Additions to Heckewelder's History of the Indians #14-21
  - Heckewelder, John Gottlieb Ernestus, 1743-1823 -- Notes, Amendments, and Additions to Heckewelder's History of the Indians #8-14
  - Ka-Hon-Hes -- Exhibition at State Museum #1, 1962; 9 items
  - Ka-Hon-Hes -- Exhibition at State Museum #2, 1962; 9 items
  - Ka-Hon-Hes -- Exhibition at State Museum #3, 1962; 19 items
  - Ka-Hon-Hes -- Ka-Hon-Hes (John Fadden) in Indian dress
  - Ka-Hon-Hes -- Mohawk Indian Paintings: Advertisement for exhibit of paintings by John Fadden (Ka-Hon-Hes), ca. 1960
  - Ka-Hon-Hes -- Photographs, n.d.
  - Leder, Lawrence H. -- Livingston Indian Records--Pictographs (samples)
  - Lutheran Church--Trappe (Pa.) -- Lutheran churches founded by Henry Melchior Muhlenberg (originally Moravians--Ilustrations)
  - Modoc Indian Oil -- Big Thunder (Ka-te-no-go), Indian boy in Indian dress; reverse is business card for Modoc Indian Oil, "Greatest Pain Medicine on Earth.", ca. 1885
  - Mohawk Indians -- Akwesasne Mohawk Counselor Organization, ca. 1949; 2 items
  - Mohawk-Tyendinaga Reserve
    - Christine, John, Ray Fadden, 1960
    - Canandaigua Treaty site, 1960
    - Sheshequin path, historical marker, 1960
    - Shikellamy, historical marker, 1960
    - Shikellamy monument, Sunbury, PA, 1960
    - Shikellamy's town, historical marker, 1960
  - Montgomery, Charles B. -- Charles B. Montgomery with self-mocking angel's halo and wings, ca. 1940
  - Montour, Joseph -- Joseph Montour and David Wallace, ca. 1936
  - Moravian Historical Society -- Indian Costumes, 1955; 6 items
    - Deerskin jacket, back view, 1955
    - Deerskin jacket, front view, 1955
    - Deerskin jacket, side view, 1955
    - Deerskin jacket, back view, fringe
    - Deerskin jacket, front view, fringe, 1955
  - Moravian Historical Society -- Indian Costumes, 1955; 5 items
  - Moravian Historical Society -- Indian Costumes, 1955
  - Moravian Historical Society -- Indian Costumes, 1955
  - Moravian Historical Society -- Indian Costumes, 1955
  - Moravians -- Lamb (Moravian seal), n.d.
  - Muhlenberg family -- Muhlenberg, Frederick Augustus, mural by George Harding at Montgomery County Courthouse, Norristown, Pa., n.d.
  - Muhlenberg family -- Muhlenberg, Henry Augustus Philip, 1782-1844, n.d.
  - Muhlenberg family -- Portraits, n.d.; 5 items
  - Muhlenberg family -- Portraits, n.d.; 5 items
  - New Fairfield (Ont.) -- Church at New Fairfield, 1950
  - New Fairfield (Ont.) -- Peters, Omer, 1950
  - New York (State) -- Alleghany and Conewaugus region, 9 items
  - O'Bail, Charles -- O'Bail, Charles and Henry
  - O'Bail, Henry -- O'Bail, Charles and Henry
  - Ohio--Miscellaneous -- Schoenbrunn Village (originally with Radabaugh, James and Mary), 10 items
  - Ohio--Miscellaneous -- Schoenbrunn Village and Gnadenhutten Massacre Monument, 1950
  - Ohio--Miscellaneous -- Schoenbrunn Village and Gnadenhutten Massacre Monument, 1950
  - Ohio--Miscellaneous -- Schoenbrunn Village and Gnadenhutten Massacre Monument, 1950
  - Ohio--Miscellaneous -- Schoenbrunn Village, n.d.; 10 items
  - Scarborough (Ont.) -- Deskaheh #3, 1956; 7 items
    - Deskaheh, 1956
    - Deskaheh in Cayuga attire, 1956
    - Archaeological site, 1956
    - Howard Skye and others, 1956
    - Man observing archaeological site, 1956
    - Preparing feast of the dead, 1956
    - Condolence ceremony
  - Scarborough (Ont.) -- Deskaheh #4, 1956
  - Scarborough (Ont.) -- Indian Village, Tabor Hill Indian Burial, 1956
  - Scarborough (Ont.) -- Indian Village, Tabor Hill Indian Burial, 1956; 2 items
  - Scarborough (Ont.) -- Indian Village, 1956; 13 items
  - Scarborough (Ont.) -- Indian Village, 1956
  - Scarborough (Ont.) -- Indian Village--Deskaheh #1, 1956; 7 items
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Reserve: Duplicates, 1955; 5 items
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Reserve: Ferry Pageant #2, 1955; 5 items
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Reserve: Ferry Pageant #3, 1955; 9 items
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Reserve: Ferry Pageant, 1955; 5 items
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Reserve: Iroquois costumes and wampum
    - George Green, native attire, back view, 1955
    - George Gree, native attire, front view, 1955
    - Jerry Aaron's son, moose-skin jacket, back view, 1955
    - Jerry Aaron's son, moose-skin jacket, side-view, 1955
    - Jerry Aaron's son, moose-skin jacket, front view, 1955
    - Mrs. Jamison, wampum, 1955
    - Mrs. Jamison, necklet, 1955
    - Mrs. George Green, full native attire, 1955
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Reserve: Iroquois costumes and wampum, 1955
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Reserve: Iroquois costumes and wampum, 1955
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Reserve: Negatives, 1955
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Reserve, 1936; 5 items
    - Douglas White, 1955
    - Chief's ferry, 1955
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Reserve, 1936; 5 items
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Reserve, 1936; 5 items
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Reserve, 1936; 5 items
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Reserve, 1936; 5 items
  - Six Nations -- Six Nations Reserve--Ohsweken, 1936; 5 items
    - Mohawk child, 1936
    - Chief Hess, 1936
    - Dance mask, 1936
    - Mr. Williams, Tuscarora, 1936
    - Cayuga longhouse, side view, 1936
    - Mohawk family, 1936
    - Cayuga longhouse, front door
    - Cayuga longhouse, landscape view, 1936
    - Nick Peters, 1936
    - Chief Joseph Montour, 1936
    - Ferry, Six Nations reserve, 1936
    - Chief Montour's house, 1936
    - Mrs. Joseph Montour, 1936
  - Tehanetorens -- Akwesasne Mohawk Counselor Organization, ca. 1949
  - Tehanetorens -- Fadden, Raymond (nephew of Tehanetorens). From folder Tehanetorens #4, 1964; 4 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Handsome Lake Bead Record (originally housed with Conrad Weiser's grave), 1955; 3 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Indian Monument at Mohawk Community Building, St. Regis, Quebec. From Tehanetorens #4, 1952; 1 item
  - Tehanetorens -- Indian monuments (some are duplicates of Six Nations material). From folder Tehanetorens #4, 1960; 8 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Indian Monuments. Some originally from Tehanetorens #4., 1960; 7 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Indian Village, Lake George: People, seven images, 1952; 12 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Indian Village, Lake George: Structures and landscapes, six images, 1952; 23 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Indian Village, Lake George, 1952; 11 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Indian Village, Lake George, 1952; 10 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Indian Village, Lake George, 1952; 13 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Indian Village, Lake George, 1952; 8 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Indian Village, Lake George, 1952; 13 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Indian Village--Deskaheh #2, 1956; 6 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Ka-Hon-Hes as a young boy, ca. 1950
  - Tehanetorens -- Mohawk Indians at Deganawidah Monument, 1952; 4 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Onchiota (N.Y.): Tehanetorens and family, 1960; 10 items
  - Tehanetorens -- Six Nations Iroquois Confederacy Record (World War II). Originally with Wallace, Paul, Indian Renaissance., ca. 1947; 1 item
  - Tehanetorens -- Six Nations Museum photographic postcards, 3 items